If you're looking for a
trusted and comprehensive health
insurance plan for you and your family, you've
come to the right place. Today, we'll compare
three major health insurance plans:
HDFC RGO Optima Store, ICICI Labs
Elevate, and Tata AIG Medical Premier. We'll
find out which plan might be a better fit for you.
Let's explore the features of these plans
in detail and see
which plan might be best for you.
Let's first talk
about the minimum entry age. With HDFC RGO
Optima Store, adult coverage
starts at 18 years, and children are
covered for 91 days.
With ICICI Labs Elevate, adult coverage
is available from six years, and children are covered from 91 days to
five years. However, with
Tata AIG Medical
Premier, adult coverage also starts at 18 years, and children are covered for 91 days. Note: If you have a floater plan, adult coverage also starts at 18 years,
and children are covered for 91 days.  If you have
small children, you will definitely get
coverage through a floater plan in ICICI Lombard Elevate.
So now comes the maximum entry
age. hdfcergo.com is
covered up to 25 years. So let's talk about
sum in short.
hdfc.com Elevate is the best option. So let's
talk about room rent limit.
In HDFC and Go Optima Store,
pre-hospitalization is covered up to 60 days and post-
hospitalization is covered up to 180 days.
In ICICI Lombard Elevate, pre-
hospitalization is covered up to 90 days and post-
hospitalization is covered up to 180 days. Talking about TA AG Medicate
Premier, in which pre-
hospitalization is covered up to 60 days and post-
hospitalization is covered up to 90 days.
Let's now also talk about the coverage of day care treatments.
Day care treatments are covered and
in ICICI Lombard Elevate also all
day care treatments are covered and TA
AG Medicate Premier has 541 treatments
covered. So if you
definitely need coverage for extensive day care treatments then
HDFC Argo Optima Store and IICR
Lum Bird Elevate plans will be very good.
Coverage of domestic treatments and modern treatments is as important for you as everything else.
So let's learn about these two plans.
HDFC Argo Optimal
Store covers both domestic treatments and
modern treatments up to the sum insured.
ICICI
Lord Elevate also covers both domestic treatments and
modern treatments up to the sum insured.
As for Tata
Medicare Premier,
both domestic treatments and modern treatments are covered up to the sum insured.
So let's talk
about coverage of non-medical expenses. HDFC
Argo Optima Store
can cover non-medical expenses as and when it comes
to ICICI Lord Elevate. Non-medical
expenses as and when it comes to
Tata Medicare Premier,
non-medical expenses
are covered as in-built coverage. So now let's talk
about the no-claim bonus.
Even in Medicate Premium,
max up to 100% will be available at Rs. 50 per year. So let us
now know about Super No Claim Bonus in
which there is no specific mention of restoration benefit
in hdfcfund.com add-on ICICI Lombard Elevate
and if we talk about TA AG Medicel
Premier, then one time
restoration is available in it for unrelated
illnesses and restoration for related illnesses is available
after 45 days. Let us now know
about waiting periods in which
initial waiting period
is 30 days in all the plans and PD waiting
period is 36 months in all the plans but
in ICICI Lombard you can reduce it to 24 or 12 months
with and on
specific treatment diseases. Waiting
period is also 24 months in all the plans
but in ICICI Lombard Elevate
it is for 90 days in BP, Diabetes and Heart conditions.  There are
exceptions. Now, lastly, comes the
unique selling points i.e., USB
hdfcergo.com plan hospitalization. If
you need treatment outside India,
you can choose the best plan according to your specific needs.
If you have
any queries, you
can ask in the comment section below. And
for such valuable information, do
not forget to subscribe to SMC Insurance.